Ariya Bayat - UNITY DEV, PROGRAMMER

□ ariyabayat788@gmail.com

in LinkedIn

Personal Summary

Seasoned Unity Developer with over 7 years of XP, from transitioning a multiplayer card game from Alpha to Closed Beta, to publishing an exciting high-speed anime platformer. Currently making AR games & experiences for Android and PC alongside artists, designers and fellow devs through technical and creative solutions, and I am keen to take on new challenges.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

GENERAL Unity | C#

AUGMENTED REALITY OpenCV | AR Foundation (ARCore + ARKit) | Python

WEB DEVELOPMENT JavaScript | HTML | CSS

BACK-END GitHub | Firebase

PRODUCTIVITY Trello | Miro | Notion | Microsoft Office

IDE Visual Studio | PyCharm | VS Code | Android Studio

OTHERS Java | WebGL

Review these projects and the code in my portfolio: https://shadyleegamer.github.io/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Humanitarian Operations | Unity Developer (AR Educational Platform)

OCT 2023 - PRESENT

Working closely with tablets, mini computers and a cross-functional team on R&D focused projects to optimise solutions for CPU and memory limitations. Assisting the Unity manager in developing core systems

- ✓ Enhanced performance at nurseries by fixing crashes through memory management using Addressables, leading to successful next day testing sessions.
- ✓ Greatly reduced product cost by £80.33 per unit by replacing depth sensor cameras with minimum webcams using OpenCV.
- ► Architecting the integration of Python and OpenCV in Unity for simulating hand and gesture tracking:
 - Boosted performance from 30 FPS to 200+ FPS by incorporating multithreading to separate image processing and video capturing into Python.
 - Built a two-way TCP connection between the Unity and Python program for transferring real-time camera feed and track data.
- ► Assisted the music department by developing a system that **automatically** generates musical notes from their MIDI files for a rhythm game.
- ▶ Implemented UI systems from design documents as well as UI tools including a Timeline skipper to assist game testers.
- Mentoring and managing tasks of junior developers and optimising their features and solutions to encourage best practices.

Okainos | Lead Developer (Online multiplayer card game)

JAN 2021 - OCT 2021

- ✓ Transitioned from Alpha to Closed Beta.
- ▶ Development & maintenance of back-end systems Integrated real-time database with over 25 accounts, multiple method OAuth authentication, web hosting and cloud storage to the game and website.
- ▶ Reduced manual updates Developed automatic update system for card changes (buffs, nerfs, tweaks) with card data assets.
- ▶ Optimization of data process Automated the writing and reading of card data between the editor and database in JSON with

Rest API through custom editor scripts.

- ► Launched Closed Beta testing campaign through web dev Built a website that attracted over 20 players resulting in valuable feedback and live testing:
 - Firebase-integrated authentication system linked to game database, enabling users to login via a single account.
 - Managed game access for beta testers to a 100 key group generated with Itch.io, stored in cloud storage.
 - Signed up to 13 accounts via mailing list, stored in real-time database.
- ► Card deck builder (SerDes) Designed a code containing details of card decks which is imported and exported by the game.
- ► Other systems such as a friends manager synced with accounts, team planner for filtering cards by properties (rarity, tribe, stats), and battle system.

PROJECTS

Edge Runner (High-speed anime platformer)

JUNE 2022 - AUG 2023

Recently published an exciting high-speed platformer game on Itch.io, featuring complex gravity-bending physics,

- ► Spline-based character controller:
 - Greatly optimized player movement by minimizing collision detections and replacing engine-physics with a custom physics solution utilizing splines.
 - Consistent physics Stress tested against extreme movement speeds and very low frame rates.
 - Assist system Aids inputs to better achieve desired actions through input buffering, dash extension and environment snapping.
- ▶ Reusing flexible systems Control lock system used to manage and prevent interruption of different special events.
- ► Extensive use of splines Developed a custom extension for Unity's Sprite Shape API that breaks splines down to segments and points for full control and flexibility. Used for:
 - Suitable movement system Solved multiple problems of custom physics through elegant use of spline points.
 - Aiding level design through real-time visualization of splines points.
- ▶ Dynamic camera Utilized Cinemachine to follow a target influenced by player movement and state to tweak the feel of each.
- ▶ Profiler analysis Maintained performance of 283 changing transforms, reducing frame time impact from 45.7% to 2.6%.

13 Game Jams MAY 2020 - MAY 2022

Worked with other programmers in teams on 13 game jams, including one ranked 15th place out of 158 entries! 6 of them were exported to WebGL. Highlights of Systems I developed:

- ▶ Dungeon level generator Random level generation sequence inspired by Spelunky.
- ▶ Object pooling Maintained performance of over 100 objects of different types present in a scene.
- ► Combo system Featuring a basic attack and two different special attack combos with pc, mobile and controller support.
- ▶ Isometric grid movement Displays movement tiles with collision detection for movable and immovable objects blocking path.

EDUCATION

Ark Walworth Academy SEP 2019 - JUL 2021

(Distinction**) BTEC Level 3 National Extended Diploma in Information Technology

Relevant units included: Computer Games Development | Programming | Mobile Apps Development | Website Development | Using Social Media in (Game Studio) Business

Hobbies: BJJ | Dancing | Music Production | Sculpting | Table Tennis | Anime